人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  Silmar
翻译  小舞
翻译 送小孩
翻译 尼克白
翻译 潇湘月影
翻译 泰斯
校对  泰斯·雪诺
校对  Silmar
时间轴 加森
时间轴 全家幸福筒
时间轴 imok
时间轴 崽猪
特效/后期 吉吉·波顿  拉图
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
总监 泰斯·雪诺
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第六集
陛下  您乐意坐坐的话  我确信...
Your Grace, if you'd like to sit, I'm sure that--
我们从中午就在等
We've been here since midday.
我经常发现东方人的时间观念与我们不同
Easterners have a difference sense of time, I've often found.
有次我在布拉佛斯等萨拉多·桑恩
Once I was waiting for Salladhor Saan here in Braavos.
我们要一起运送三船上好的...
Together, we were going to run three shiploads of the finest...
欢迎来到铁金库
Welcome to the Iron Bank.
请坐
Please, sit.
有什么可以效劳的  史坦尼斯大人
What can we do for you, Lord Stannis?
你们面前的是拜拉席恩家族的史坦尼斯
This is Stannis of the House Baratheon,
安达尔人和先民的国王
King of the Andals and the First Men,
七国的统治者暨全境守护
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm.
现今占据铁王座的
The Iron Throne is currently occupied
是拜拉席恩家族的托曼
by Tommen of the House Baratheon,
安达尔人和先民的国王
King of the Andals and the First Men,
七国的统治者暨全境守护
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms and Protector of the Realm.
他不是我的血亲
He shares no blood with me.
他是乱伦所生的孽种
He is a bastard born of incest.
和他死去的哥哥一样
As was his brother before him.
是的  我们听过这个故事
Yes, we have heard this story.
这不是故事  这是事实
It's not a story. It's the truth.
国王的外祖父有不同的故事
The king's grandfather tells a different story.
讲的是嫉妒心作祟的叔父
A story about a jealous uncle
企图篡夺合法国王的王座
whose attempts to usurp the throne from the rightful king
使得七大王国付出了无数鲜血和金子
cost the Seven Kingdoms dearly in blood and gold.
你借给他的金子
Gold you loaned him.
而你认为血统给了你向我们讨金子的资格
And you feel your blood gives you a claim on our gold?
世上没人比我更有资格
More than any man living.
狭海对岸  你们的书中充斥着
Across the Narrow Sea, your books are filled
"篡夺者"  "疯子"  "血统继承"
with words like "usurper" and "madman"
这些字眼
and "blood right."
在这里  我们的书里满是数字
Here, our books are filled with numbers.
我们更喜欢数字讲述的故事
We prefer the stories they tell.
更直白
More plain.
更难曲解
Less open to interpretation.
你麾下还有多少兵士
How many fighting men remain loyal to you?
四千
4,000.
你有多少艘船
And how many ships do you have?
还浮在水上的  戴佛斯爵士
The ones still afloat, Ser Davos,
不是沉在黑水湾底的
not at the bottom of Blackwater Bay.
三十二艘
32.
你们龙石岛上出产多少
And how much wheat and barley and beef
小麦  大麦  牛肉  猪肉
and pork do you produce on Dragonstone
养活这四千人和三十二艘船
to feed your 4,000 men on your 32 ships?
没有
None.
你也看得出为何在我们看来
You can see why these numbers seem unlikely to add up
这些数字预示不出美好的结局
to a happy ending from our perspective.
恐怕我们只好婉拒你的请求
I'm afraid we must respectfully decline your request.
但是还要多谢你亲自光临
But we thank you for paying us the honor of your visit.
大人
My lord.
我不是大人  戴佛斯·席渥斯爵士
I'm not a lord, Ser Davos Seaworth.
你在这儿也当不了爵爷
You would not be either here.
在布拉佛斯
In Braavos,
是不会赏给窃贼封号的
thieves are not rewarded with titles.
严格来说  我没强取豪夺
Well, strictly speaking, I didn't do the thieving.
那是海盗的作为
That would be the pirates.
我不过是将他们所获从一处运往另一处
I just moved what they stole from one place to another.
这就是史坦尼斯国王对我所犯之罪的惩罚
This is the payment that was demanded by King Stannis for my crimes.
我认为赏罚严明无欺
I consider it an honest accounting.
他是个诚实的人  也是你们最好的机会
He's an honest man and he's your best chance
收回丢进维斯特洛无底洞的钱
to get back the money you've sunk into Westeros.
我想那是一大笔钱  战争是很昂贵的
Which is a lot, I imagine. Wars are expensive.
战争已经结束
The war is over.
只要史坦尼斯还活着  战争就没有结束
As long as Stannis lives, the war is not over.
谁才是君临真正的掌权人
Who's the real power in King's Landing?
-戴佛斯爵士  -请回答
- Ser Davos... - Humor me.
-泰温·兰尼斯特  -泰温·兰尼斯特多大
- Tywin Lannister. - How old is Tywin Lannister?
-六十七  -六十七  他死后谁来掌权
- 67. - 67. And when he dies, who's in command?
一个乱伦所生的半大男孩
A half-grown boy, the product of incest?
瑟曦·兰尼斯特  被臣民瞧不起的太后
Cersei Lannister, a queen whose people despise her?
詹姆·兰尼斯特  最负盛名的事迹是杀害
Jaime Lannister, a man best known for killing the king
他誓言保护的国王
he was sworn to protect?
泰温死后  你们支持谁
When Tywin's gone, who do you back?
那是以后的问题
That is a problem for another time.
抱歉  我认为这问题迫在眉睫
Begging your pardon, I think it's a problem for now.
维斯特洛只剩一位可靠的领袖
There's only one reliable leader left in Westeros.
史坦尼斯
Stannis.
他有继承权
He's got the birthright.
正当盛年
He's in his prime.
他是久经考验的统帅
He's a tried and tested battle commander.
而且还债的时候绝不耍嘴皮子
And he doesn't just talk about paying people back,
而是付诸行动
he does it.
瞭望哨看到一艘海盗船冲他们而来
The lookout sees a pirate ship sailing their way.
船长喊大副
The captain shouts to his first mate,
"拿我的红上衣来"
"Bring me my red shirt."
大副拿来红上衣  船长穿在身上
The first mate brings the red shirt and the captain puts it on.
当海盗试图登船
And when the pirates try to board,
勇敢的船长带领手下赢得了胜利
the brave captain leads his men to victory.
几天之后  瞭望哨大叫
A few days later, the lookout screams,
"两艘海盗船"
"Two pirate ships!"
船员抖如筛糠
The crew is shivering like scared mice.
但是英勇无畏的船长高呼
But the courageous captain hollers,
"拿我的红上衣来"
"Bring me my red shirt!"
战斗结束后  大副问
After the battle, the first mate asks,
"船长  为什么开战前你要穿红上衣"
"Captain, why do you call for your red shirt before battle?"
船长答道
The captain replies,
"这样即使我受伤  你们也看不到我流血"
"So that if I am stabbed, you will not see me bleed."
第二天一早  瞭望哨尖声叫嚷
The next morning the lookout screams,
"十艘海盗船
"10 pirate ships!
我们被包围了"
We are surrounded!"
船员们沉默了
The crew goes silent.
他们看向勇敢的船长
They all look to their brave captain,
等待他惯常的号令
waiting for his usual command.
船长冷静如常  大喝一声
Calm as ever, the captain bellows...
"拿我的屎黄色裤子来"
"Bring me my brown pants!"
你以为她们见过不讲这段子的海盗吗
You think they ever met a pirate who didn't tell them that joke?
戴佛斯
Davos.
听说你正在龙石岛的地牢里烂着呢
I heard you were rotting in a dungeon in Dragonstone.
只烂了一半
Only half rotted.
来加入我们  朋友  来吧
Join us, my friend. Join us.
这位是娜拉
This is Lhara.
-这位是...  -我才是娜拉
- And this is-- - I am Lhara.
她可是个艺术家  真的
She's an artist, this one, truly.
不好意思  没时间  我们黎明就起航
No time, I'm afraid. We sail at sunrise.
我们
We?
你和我  我们
You, me-- we.
从前我以为这男人爱我
Once I thought this man loved me.
现在才知道他瞧不起我
Now I know he despises me.
他想看我穷困孤单地死在寒冷的...
He wants to see me die poor and alone on some cold--
你不会孤单
You won't be alone.
也不会受穷
And you won't be poor.
还有一箱子好东西丢在你家里
There's a chest of the good stuff left back at your house.
交给你妻子了
I gave it to your wife.
你真不够朋友  我的朋友
You're not my friend, my friend.
黎明再见
I'll see you at sunrise.
"我限你满月前
"I give you until the full moon
命令所有铁渣离开北境
to order all ironborn scum out of the North
回到你们称其为家的屎群岛
and back to those shit-stained rocks you call home.
满月第一夜
On the first night of the full moon,
我会肃清所有仍在我们领土上的岛民
I will hunt down every islander still on our lands
并活剥其皮
and flay them living,
就像我剥在临冬城发现的
the way I flayed the 20 ironborn scum
那二十个铁渣一样
I found at Winterfell.
盒中有份特别的礼物
In the box you'll find a special gift--
是席恩最爱的玩具
Theon's favorite toy.
我夺走时他哭了
He cried when I took it away from him.
立刻离开北境  否则席恩将一份份
Leave the North now or more boxes will follow
随盒而至
with more Theon.
署名  拉姆斯·雪诺
Signed Ramsay Snow,
恐怖堡公爵
natural born son of Roose Bolton,
和北境守护
Lord of the Dreadfort
卢斯·波顿之子"
and Warden of the North."
爽
Yes!
他们剥我们同胞的皮
They skinned our countrymen
残害我的弟弟
and they mutilated my brother,
你们的王子
your prince.
Your prince.
他们对我弟弟如何
Everything they've done to him,
也就是对你们如何
they've also done to you.
爽  爽
Yes! Yes!
若是他们伤害我们的王子  却不用付出代价
As long as they can hurt our prince with impunity,
铁种两个字就白叫了
the word ironborn means nothing.
去左边
Go left.
-席恩·葛雷乔伊  -我不知道...
- Theon Greyjoy. - I don't know--
我来找席恩·葛雷乔伊
I'm here for Theon Greyjoy.
带我去地牢
Take me to the dungeons.
他不在地牢
He's not in the dungeons.
-最右边的笼子  -谢谢
- Last cage on the right. - Thank you.
这边
This way!
我们回家
We're going home.
不
No!
没事了  是我  雅拉
It's all right. It's me, Yara.
你骗不了我
You can't trick me.
告诉他  告诉他你骗不了我
Tell him. Tell him you couldn't trick me.
我没骗你  席恩  我来救你
I'm not tricking you, Theon. I'm saving you.
不是席恩  是臭佬
Not Theon! Reek!
臭佬  我的名字是臭佬
Reek! My name is Reek!
如果被他们堵在这儿  我们就出不去了
If they catch us in here, we're trapped.
帮我拉他一把
Help me with him.
不  不要
No, you can't!
-不要  -你是席恩·葛雷乔伊
- You can't! - You're Theon Greyjoy.
不  我不相信她  我知道我是谁
No, I don't believe her! I know who I am!
我是臭佬  臭佬  忠诚的臭佬
I'm Reek! Reek! Loyal Reek!
听话的臭佬  我一直都是臭佬
Good Reek! I've always been Reek!
真是一个美好的夜晚
This is turning into a lovely evening.
我是臭佬  忠诚的臭佬
I'm Reek! Loyal Reek!
席恩
Theon!
把我弟弟还给我  就饶了你其余的手下
Give me my brother and no more of your men will die.
你的卵蛋可比他以前的大多了
You've got bigger balls than he ever did.
可你挂着这么大的卵蛋
But with those big balls of yours...
又能跑多快呢
how fast can you run?
划到大船去  快
Make for the ship, now.
但你弟弟还没来
But your brother.
我弟弟死了
My brother is dead.
我要让你享受一把
I have a treat for you.
作为奖励
A reward.
奖励
Reward?
是的  臭佬
Yes, Reek.
昨晚闯进来的那些畜生
Those creatures who came in the night,
他们想带走你
they wanted to take you away.
但你没让他们得逞
And you didn't let them.
你表现得很忠诚
You remained loyal.
我...我不想被他们带走
I-- I didn't want them to take me.
我害怕极了
I was so scared.
-我不想让他们...  -是的  臭佬
- I didn't want them-- - Yes, yes, Reek.
泡个澡吧
It's a bath.
给你准备的
For you.
把身上的破布脱了
Remove those rags.
快点
Now.
还有裤子  臭佬
The britches, too, Reek.
把裤子脱了
Take them off.
你爱我吗  臭佬
Do you love me, Reek?
当然爱  大人
Yes, of course, my lord.
很好
Good.
因为我要你为我做件事
Because I need you to do something for me.
非常重要的事
Something very important.
有一座城堡  你知道的
There's a castle, you see.
一帮坏人占领了那座城堡
Some bad men hold this castle.
我要你帮我夺回这座城堡
I need your help to take this castle back.
可我怎样...
But how can--
我要你演个角色
I need you to play a role.
假扮成另一个人
To pretend to be someone you're not.
假扮成谁
Pretend to be who?
席恩·葛雷乔伊
Theon Greyjoy.
你面前的是坦格利安家族的"风暴降生"
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安一世
不焚者
弥林女王
安达尔人和先民的女王
草海上的卡丽熙
解放者  龙之母
别害怕  我的朋友
女王请你上前说话
他是个牧羊人
He is a goatherd.
他说他曾祈祷您能战胜奴隶主们
He says he prayed for your victory against the slave masters.
我感谢他的祈祷
I thank him for his prayers.
他说是您的龙所为
It was your dragons, he says.
它们今早袭击了他的羊群
They came this morning for his flock.
他希望自己没有冒犯女王陛下
He hopes he has not offended Your Grace,
但他现在一无所有
but now he has nothing.
告诉他  对于他遭受的苦难  我很抱歉
Tell this man I am sorry for his hardship.
我没法让他的山羊起死回生
I cannot bring back his goats,
但我会以三倍的价格赔偿他
but I will see he is paid their value three times over.
召见下一个
Send the next one in.
西茨达拉·佐·洛拉克大人向女王陛下请愿
西茨达拉·佐·洛拉克大人可以自己张嘴
丹妮莉丝女王
Queen Daenerys.
您的美貌如传闻中一样夺目
Tales of your beauty were not exaggerated.
谢谢你
I thank you.
洛拉克是弥林最古老和荣耀的家族
Mine is one of the oldest and proudest families in Meereen.
我很荣幸接见你
Then it is my honor to receive you.
我的父亲是弥林最受尊敬
My father, one of Meereen's most respected
和爱戴的市民  他负责监督
and beloved citizens, oversaw the restoration
弥林伟大建筑的重建和维护
and maintenance of its greatest landmarks.
包括这座金字塔
This pyramid included.
那我可要感谢他的功劳
For that, he has my gratitude.
我应该见见他
I should be honored to meet him.
您见过了  陛下
You have, Your Grace.
您将他钉死了
You crucified him.
我祈祷您在有生之年
I pray you'll never live to see
不会看到亲人遭此毒手
a member of your family treated so cruelly.
你父亲钉死了无辜的孩童
Your father crucified innocent children.
我父亲反对钉死那些孩童
My father spoke out against crucifying those children.
他谴责这一罪行  但是被驳回了
He decried it as a criminal act, but was overruled.
以罪行回应罪行  这算公道吗
Is it justice to answer one crime with another?
我对你失去父亲感到遗憾
I am sorry you no longer have a father,
但我对伟主们的处置不是罪行
but my treatment of the masters was no crime.
你要谨记这一点
You'd be wise to remember that.
木已成舟
What's done is done.
您是女王  而我是弥林的仆人
You are the queen and I am a servant of Meereen.
我不希望这里的传统被连根拔去
A servant who does not wish to see its traditions eradicated.
你所说的传统是什么
And what traditions do you speak of?
葬礼仪式
The tradition of funeral rite.
体面地安葬在圣恩神庙中
Proper burial in the Temple of the Graces.
我父亲和一百六十二名弥林贵族
My father and 162 noble Meereenese
仍然被钉在柱子上
are still nailed to those posts,
受秃鹫啄食  在阳光下腐烂
carrion for vultures, rotting in the sun.
陛下  我请求您命令放下这些人
Your Grace, I ask that you order these men taken down
让他们能够被体面地安葬
so that they might receive proper burials.
那些被高贵的弥林人钉死的奴隶孩童怎么办
And what of the slave children these noble Meereenese crucified?
他们也在阳光下腐烂
They were rotting in the sun as well.
你会请求我体面地安葬他们吗
Would you have begged me for their right to a proper burial?
陛下  我不能为伟主们的行为辩护
Your Grace, I cannot defend the actions of the masters.
我只能以一个敬爱父亲的儿子的身份请求您
I can only speak to you as a son who loved his father.
让我取下他的尸首
Let me take his body down.
让我将他带到神庙
Let me have him brought to the temple
体面地安葬
and buried with dignity
让他在阴间求得安宁
so that he might find peace in the next world.
安葬你的父亲吧  西茨达拉·佐·洛拉克
Bury your father, Hizdahr zo Loraq.
谢谢您  我的女王
Thank you, my queen.
还有多少人
How many more?
还有二百一十二个请愿者等待觐见  陛下
There are 212 supplicants waiting, Your Grace.
二百一十二个
212?
召见下一个
Send the next one in.
会议不是每回都这么早开始吧
These meetings aren't always going to be this early, are they?
我昨天睡得晚
I was up late last night.
说起来  我是不是算个什么大臣了
So, does this mean I am a master of something now?
财政  海政
Coins, ships?
泰温大人和我早已决定
Lord Tywin and I already determined
由我担任海政大臣  那时你还没...
that I shall be the Master of Ships long before you--
泰温大人  能出席御前会议
Lord Tywin, it's a great honor
在下倍感荣幸  我...
to have been granted a seat on this council. I--
审判今天下午开始
The trial begins this afternoon.
我们只有一上午的时间处理国事
We only have the morning for affairs of state.
开始吧
Shall we begin?
有人在河间地见到桑铎·克里冈  大人
Sandor Clegane has been spotted in the Riverlands, my lord.
懦夫和叛徒
A coward and a traitor.
我的小小鸟儿说猎狗杀了我们五个士兵
My birds tell me the Hound slaughtered five of our soldiers.
我相信他还说了"去他妈的国王"
I believe the phrase "fuck the king" was uttered.
可耻
Disgraceful.
给多少钱能让普通士兵
What would it take to make the common soldier
脑袋发热  愿与猎狗搏命
stupid enough to try his luck with the Hound?
十枚银鹿足矣
10 silver stags seems a generous bounty.
加到一百枚  还有何事
Make it 100. What else?
东方又传来了消息  大人
More whispers from the east, my lord.
那个坦格利安家的女孩吗
The Targaryen girl?
丹妮莉丝已在弥林安定下来
Daenerys has taken up residence in Meereen.
她征服了那座城市  成了那里的女王
She has conquered the city and rules as its queen.
拿什么征服的
Conquered with what?
她带领着一支无垢者大军  太后
She commands an army of Unsullied, my queen.
约有八千人
Some 8,000 strong.
还有佣兵次子团相助
She has a company of sellswords-- the Second Sons.
她有两位骑士进言
She has two knights advising her--
乔拉·莫尔蒙和巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
Jorah Mormont and Barristan Selmy.
而且她还有三条龙
And she has three dragons.
三条幼龙
Baby dragons.
它们一年比一年大  陛下
Larger every year, Your Grace.
莫尔蒙是我们派去监视她的探子
Mormont is spying on her for us.
不再是了  他现在似乎完全效忠于她
No longer. He appears to be fully devoted to her.
至于巴利斯坦爵士  看起来
As for Ser Barristan, it would seem
我们低估了他对被剥夺御林铁卫身份的不满
he took his dismissal from the Kingsguard a bit harder than anticipated.
他老了
He's an old man.
没法保护我儿子
He wasn't fit to protect my son.
在他护卫时  乔佛里没有死
Joffrey didn't die on his watch.
将他免职是为羞辱  而且愚蠢至极
Dismissing him was as insulting as it was stupid.
别告诉我您还担心世界另一头的孩子
Don't tell me you're worried about a child halfway across the world.
这个孩子的身边有两位老将辅佐
A child with two seasoned warriors counseling her
身后有一支强大的军队  太后陛下
and a powerful army at her back, Your Grace.
瓦里斯大人说得对
Lord Varys is right.
我在厄索斯亲眼见过无垢者
I have been to Essos and seen the Unsullied firsthand.
他们打起仗来很有一套
They are very impressive on the battlefield.
但床上功夫逊色不少
Less so in the bedroom.
三百年来  依靠龙没打胜过一场仗
Dragons haven't won a war in 300 years.
赢得战争的从来都是军队
Armies win them all the time.
我们必须解决掉她
She must be dealt with.
怎么解决  大人
How, my lord?
用武力吗
By force?
逼不得已当然要这么做
Eventually, if it comes to that.
你那些小小鸟去得了弥林吗
Can your little birds find their way into Meereen?
应是没有问题  首相大人
Most certainly, my Lord Hand.
提利尔大人  劳烦你
Mmm. Lord Tyrell, be a good man.
拿我的纸笔来
Fetch my quill and paper.
奥柏伦亲王
Prince Oberyn.
瓦里斯大人...
Lord Varys...
瓦里斯就行了  我并非贵族
Only Varys. I'm not actually a nobleman.
不必称我为"大人"
No one is under obligation to call me lord.
但大家都这么称呼你
And yet everyone does.
您似乎很了解无垢者
You seem quite knowledgeable about the Unsullied.
在厄索斯待过很长时间吗
Did you spend much time in Essos?
五年
Five years.
能告诉我原因吗
May I ask why?
这个世界如此辽阔美丽
'Tis a big and beautiful world.
而大多数人从生到死
Most of us live and die
都在同一个角落里不挪窝
in the same corner where we were born
没见识过别处的风景
and never get to see any of it.
我不想成为那种人
I don't want to be most of us.
谁叫我们大多数人不是亲王呢
Most of us aren't princes.
你是厄索斯人
You are from Essos.
具体是哪里  里斯吗
Where? Lys?
我听得出口音
I have an ear for accents.
我早就没有口音了
I've lost my accent entirely.
这我也听出来了
I have an ear for that as well.
你是怎么来这儿的
How did you get here?
说来话长
It's a long story.
只是不想告诉别人
One you don't like telling people.
只说给我信任的人
People I trust.
我的情妇艾拉莉亚一定会觉得你很有意思
My paramour Ellaria, she would find you very interesting.
你应该去妓院见见她
You should come to the brothel and meet her.
我们自备了美酒  可不像他们这儿的泔水
We brought our own wine, not the swill they serve here.
还有些可爱的小伙子陪着  不过...
We have some lovely boys on retainer, but...
你以前喜欢小伙子吧
You did like boys before?
是吗
Really?
那就是喜欢姑娘了
Girls? Hmm.
希望你别见怪
I hope you won't be offended
万万没想到你竟然喜欢姑娘
when I say I never would have guessed.
没关系
Not at all.
但我对姑娘也不感兴趣
But I was never interested in girls, either.
-那你喜欢什么  -什么都不喜欢
- What then? - Nothing.
每个人都有喜好
Everybody is interested in something.
我不一样
Not me.
当我看到欲望对人的影响
When I see what desire does to people,
对这个国家的影响
what it's done to this country,
我很高兴没有参与其中
I am very glad to have no part in it.
此外  人若不为欲念驱使
Besides, the absence of desire
便能放开手脚追求别的东西
leaves one free to pursue other things.
比如
Such as?
让我猜猜  我被赦免了
Let me guess, I've been pardoned.
真要这样吗
Really?
这是父亲的命令
Father's orders.
是啊  我们绝不能让父亲失望
Well, we mustn't disappoint Father.
弑君者
Kingslayer!
我  拜拉席恩家族的托曼一世
I, Tommen of the House Baratheon, first of my Name,
安达尔人和先民的国王
King of the Andals and the First Men,
七国的统治者
and Lord of the Seven Kingdoms,
在此宣布  我本人不参与庭审
do hereby recuse myself from this trial.
由全境守护者  御前首相
Tywin of the House Lannister, Hand of the King,
兰尼斯特家族的泰温  替我主持审判
Protector of the Realm, will sit as judge in my stead.
协助他审判的还有马泰尔家族的奥柏伦亲王
And with him Prince Oberyn of the House Martell
以及提利尔家族的梅斯大人
and Lord Mace of the House Tyrell.
若被告确实有罪
And if found guilty...
愿诸神严惩不贷
may the gods punish the accused.
兰尼斯特家族的提利昂
Tyrion of the House Lannister,
摄政太后指控你犯有弑君大罪
you stand accused by the Queen Regent of regicide.
是你杀害了乔佛里国王吗
Did you kill King Joffrey?
不是
No.
是你的妻子  珊莎夫人干的吗
Did your wife, the Lady Sansa?
据我所知不是
Not that I know of.
那你说  他是怎么死的
How would you say he died, then?
他是被鸽子馅饼噎死的
Choked on his pigeon pie.
依你之见  罪在厨师
So you would blame the bakers?
不然就是鸽子  反正怪不到我头上
Or the pigeons. Just leave me out of it.
传召第一位证人
The crown may call its first witness.
我们刚护着乔佛里国王从暴民中撤出
Once we'd got King Joffrey safely away from the mob,
小恶魔就突然发飙了
the Imp rounded on him.
他狠狠地给了国王一记耳光
He slapped the king across the face
还骂陛下是残暴的蠢王
and called him a vicious idiot and a fool.
那不是小恶魔第一次威胁乔佛里
It wasn't the first time the Imp threatened Joffrey.
就在这间王座厅里
Right here in this throne room,
他曾冲上台阶  大骂国王是蠢鹅
he marched up those steps and called our king a halfwit.
还将先王陛下与疯王相提并论
Compared his Grace to the Mad King
言下之意  先王陛下必不得好死
and suggested he'd meet the same fate.
见我替国王争辩
And when I spoke in the king's defense,
他竟威胁要杀了我
he threatened to have me killed.
你怎么不告诉大家乔佛里当时在做什么
Oh, why don't you tell them what Joffrey was doing?
-肃静  -他拿上膛的弩对着珊莎·史塔克
- Silence. - Pointing a loaded crossbow at Sansa Stark
你则撕扯她的衣服  还殴打她
while you tore at her clothes and beat her.
肃静
Silence!
没问到你  不准答话
You will not speak unless called upon.
你下去吧  马林爵士
You're dismissed, Ser Meryn.
石蜥毒
Basilisk venom,
寡妇之血
widow's blood,
附子草
wolfsbane,
夜影之水
essence of nightshade,
甜睡花
sweetsleep,
里斯之泪
tears of Lys,
鬼舞草
demon's dance...
瞎眼毒
blindeye--
你的意思很明白了  大学士
I think you have made your point, Grand Maester.
你库中有不少毒药
You have a lot of poison in your store.
早没了  奥柏伦亲王
Had, Prince Oberyn.
我的库藏被劫掠一空
My stores were plundered.
谁抢走的
By whom?
被告提利昂·兰尼斯特
By the accused, Tyrion Lannister,
这之前他以莫须有的罪名将我囚禁
after he had me wrongfully imprisoned.
大学士
Grand Maester,
你检验过乔佛里国王的遗体
you examined King Joffrey's corpse.
他是否确实被人毒杀
Was it without question poison that killed him?
毫无疑问
Without question.
这是在国王的弄臣
This was found on the body of
唐托斯·霍拉德的尸体上找到的
Dontos Hollard, the king's fool.
他最后一次露面时  将被告的妻子
He was last seen spiriting Sansa Stark,
珊莎·史塔克偷偷带离了婚宴
the wife of the accused, away from the feast.
婚礼当天
She wore this necklace
她戴的正是这条项链
the day of the wedding.
里面发现了一种
Residue of a most rare
最稀有最可怕的毒药的残渣
and terrible poison was found inside.
是从你那里偷走的毒药吗
Was this one of the poisons stolen from your store?
是的  扼死者
It was. The Strangler.
七国内只有少数人拥有这种毒药
A poison few in the Seven Kingdoms possess.
被告正是用它杀死了
And used to strike down the most noble child
受诸神眷顾而降生的天命之子
the gods ever put on this good earth.
"今日之辱  我一定会报
"I will hurt you for this.
总有一天  当你自以为平安快活时
A day will come when you think you are safe and happy
喜悦必将在你嘴里化成灰烬
and your joy will turn to ashes in your mouth
到时你便知道  债已偿清"
and you will know the debt is paid."
你亲弟弟这么对你说的
Your own brother said this to you?
就在黑水湾大战之前不久
Shortly before the Battle of Blackwater Bay.
我质疑他将乔佛里
I confronted him about his plans
推上前线的计划
to put Joffrey on the front lines.
后来  攻城开始后
As it turned out, when the attack came,
小乔坚持留在城墙上
Joff insisted on remaining at the battlements.
他认为国王在场能鼓舞士气
He believed his presence would inspire the troops.
提利昂说
Tyrion said,
"到时你便知道  债已偿清"
"And you will know the debt is paid."
什么债
What debt?
我发现他在首相塔里
I discovered he'd been keeping whores
蓄养娼妓
in the Tower of the Hand.
我要他去妓院狎妓
I asked him to confine his salacious acts
以免有失体面
to the brothel where such behavior belongs.
他很不高兴
He wasn't pleased.
太后陛下  感谢您站出来当庭作证
Thank you, Your Grace, for the courage of your testimony.
你还记得他具体是怎么威胁的吗
Do you remember the precise nature of this threat?
记得  大人
I'm afraid I do, my lord.
他说  "那你或许该对我客气点
He said, "Perhaps you should speak more softly to me, then.
怪物很危险
Monsters are dangerous
而现在国王正如蚊蝇般死去"
and just now kings are dying like flies."
这是他在御前会议上说的吗
And he said this to you at a meeting of the small council?
是的
Yes.
在收到罗柏·史塔克的死讯之后
After we received word of Robb Stark's death.
他听到这消息似乎并不高兴
He didn't seem gladdened by the news.
也许与珊莎·史塔克成婚
Perhaps his marriage to Sansa Stark
令他对北方佬抱有同情之心
had made him more sympathetic to the northern cause.
下去吧  瓦里斯大人
You're excused, Lord Varys.
父亲  我能问证人一个问题吗
Father, may I ask the witness one question?
就一个
One.
你曾说过
You once said
如果没有我  都城必会沦陷
that without me, this city would have faced certain defeat.
你说史书不会记载我的姓名
You said the histories would never mention me,
你却不会忘记
but you would not forget.
你忘了吗  瓦里斯大人
Have you forgotten, Lord Varys?
遗憾的是  大人
Sadly, my lord,
我从不遗忘
I never forget a thing.
暂时休庭
We will adjourn for now.
一小时后鸣钟开庭
Toll the bells in an hour's time.
退席
Clear the court!
您要判您的亲生儿子死刑吗
You'd condemn your own son to death?
我谁也没判  审判尚未结束
I've condemned no one. The trial is not over.
这不是审判  是场闹剧
This isn't a trial. It's a farce.
您知道这全都是瑟曦操纵的
Cersei has manipulated everything and you know it.
我不知还有这等事
I know nothing of the sort.
-您向来厌恶提利昂  -他杀了国王
- You've always hated Tyrion. - He killed his king.
我也一样
As did I.
您知道疯王对我下的最后一道命令是什么吗
Do you know the last order the Mad King gave me?
把您的首级呈给他
To bring him your head.
我救了您的命  好让您谋杀我弟弟吗
I saved your life so you could murder my brother?
-这不是谋杀  是主持公道  -公道
- It won't be murder. It'll be justice. - Justice?
我在履行身为御前首相的责任
I'm performing my sworn duty as Hand of the King.
如果提利昂有罪  便应将他依罪惩处
If Tyrion is found guilty, he will be punished accordingly.
-他会被处决  -不  是依罪惩处
- He'll be executed. - No, he'll be punished accordingly.
您曾说过  家族就是传承  永远延续
Once you said family is what lives on. All that lives on.
您说过要建立一个传承千年不朽的王朝
You told me about a dynasty that would last 1,000 years.
提利昂一死  您的王朝怎么办
What happens to your dynasty when Tyrion dies?
我是御林铁卫
I'm a Kingsguard,
发誓不娶妻生子
forbidden by oath to carry on the family line.
我很清楚你的誓言
I'm well aware of your oath.
您的姓氏怎么办
What happens to your name?
将来在战场上  谁来打起狮子旗
Who carries the lion banner into future battles?
您的侄子吗
Your nephews?
蓝赛尔·兰尼斯特吗
Lancel Lannister?
还是那些个我连名字都记不清的家伙
Others whose names I don't even remember?
若我宽恕杀害我外孙的凶手
What happens to my dynasty
我的王朝又会怎样
if I spare the life of my grandson's killer?
会由我延续下去
It survives through me.
我将卸任御林铁卫
I'll leave the Kingsguard.
只要您放提利昂一条生路
I'll take my place as your son and heir
我就继承您的家业
if you let Tyrion live.
成交
Done.
等取证结束  宣判有罪后
When the testimony's concluded and a guilty verdict rendered,
提利昂将有机会为自己进言
Tyrion will be given the chance to speak.
他请求宽恕  我便准许他加入守夜人
He'll plead for mercy. I'll allow him to join the Night's Watch.
三天后  他将启程前往黑城堡
In three days' time, he'll depart for Castle Black
在长城度过余生
and live out his days at the Wall.
你则即刻脱下白袍
You'll remove your white cloak immediately.
离开君临
You will leave King's Landing
继承凯岩城公爵之位
to assume your rightful place at Casterly Rock.
娶个门当户对的女人
You will marry a suitable woman
为兰尼斯特家传宗接代
and father children named Lannister.
永远不准再背弃家族
And you'll never turn your back on your family again.
一言为定
You have my word.
And you have mine.
不太顺利是吧
Not going well, is it?
-你将被判有罪  -你也这么觉得吗
- You're going to be found guilty. - Oh, you think so?
宣判后  你要正式请求宽恕
When you are, you need to enter a formal plea for mercy
请求发配去长城
and ask to be sent to the Wall.
父亲会准的
Father's agreed to it.
他会网开一面  准你穿上黑衣
He'll spare your life and allow you to join the Night's Watch.
奈德·史塔克不也得到了同样的承诺
Ned Stark was promised the same thing
我们都清楚他的下场
and we both know how that turned out.
父亲不是乔佛里  他会守信
Father is not Joffrey. He'll keep his word.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
你相信我吗
Do you trust me?
嘴巴闭紧  不要口无遮拦
Keep your mouth shut. No more outbursts.
很快就会结束的
This will all be over soon.
传召下一位证人
The crown may call its next witness.
报上名字
State your name.
雪伊
Shae.
你愿意对诸神发誓
Do you swear by all the gods
所说的证词全都真实可靠吗
that your testimony will be true and honest?
我发誓
I swear it.
你认识这个人吗
Do you know this man?
是的  提利昂·兰尼斯特
Yes. Tyrion Lannister.
你怎么认识他的
How do you know him?
我是他妻子珊莎夫人的侍女
I was handmaiden to his wife Lady Sansa.
此人被指控谋杀乔佛里国王
This man stands accused of murdering King Joffrey.
你知道些什么
What do you know of this?
我知道他有罪
I know that he's guilty.
他和珊莎一起密谋弑君
He and Sansa planned it together.
肃静
Silence!
继续说
Continue.
她想为父亲  母亲和哥哥报仇
She wanted revenge for her father, her mother, her brother.
她把他们的死都怪到国王头上
She blamed their deaths on the king.
提利昂乐意帮忙
Tyrion was happy to help.
他恨乔佛里  恨太后
He hated Joffrey. He hated the queen.
也恨您  大人
He hated you, my lord.
他从大学士的房间偷来毒药
He stole poison from the Grand Maester's chamber
放进乔佛里的酒中
to put in Joffrey's wine.
你如何知道这么多
How could you possibly know all this?
他为什么要向妻子的侍女泄露计划
Why would he reveal such plans to his wife's maid?
我不仅是她的侍女
I wasn't just her maid.
我还是他的妓女
I was his whore.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
你说你是他的...
You said you were his...
妓女
His whore.
他是怎么找上你的
How did you come to be in his service?
是他抢走的
He stole me.
我当时跟着别人  大人麾下的一名骑士
I was with another man, a knight in your lordship's army.
提利昂来到军营后
But when Tyrion arrived at the camp,
派一个歹人进了我们帐篷
he sent one of his cutthroats into our tent.
打折了骑士的胳膊
He broke the knight's arm
把我带去给了提利昂大人
and brought me to Lord Tyrion.
"你现在是我的了"  他说
"You belong to me now," He said.
"我要你拿出浑身解数
"I want you to fuck me
就当今晚是我人生最后一晚"
like it's my last night in this world."
肃静  肃静
Silence. Silence!
你做了吗
And did you?
我做了什么
Did I what?
你拿出了浑身解数  就当是他人生最后一晚
Fuck him like it was his last night in this world.
他所有的要求我都照办
I did everything he wanted.
无论他要我做什么
Whatever he told me to do to him.
无论他想对我做什么
Whatever he felt like doing to me.
他要我亲哪里我都亲
I kissed him where he wanted.
他要我舔哪里我都舔
I licked him where he wanted.
他要插进哪里我都配合
I let him put himself where he wanted.
我只是他的财物
I was his property.
我会在他房间等上好几个小时
I would wait in his chambers for hours
方便他无聊时拿我取乐
so he could use me when he was bored.
他还命我称他为"我的雄狮"  我照做了
He ordered me to call him "my lion," so I did.
我捧着他的脸说
I took his face in my hands and said,
"我是你的  你是我的"
"I am yours and you are mine."
雪伊
Shae.
别说了
Please don't.
我是个妓女
I am a whore.
记得吗
Remember?
那都是在他娶珊莎之前
That was before he married Sansa.
结婚以后  他只想要她
After that, all he wanted was her.
但珊莎不让他上床
But she wouldn't let him into her bed.
所以他答应为她杀死乔佛里国王
So he promised to kill King Joffrey for her.
父亲
Father.
我要招供
I wish to confess.
我要  招供
I wish... to confess.
你要招供
You wish to confess?
我救过你们
I saved you.
我拯救过这座城
I saved this city
和你们分文不值的贱命
and all your worthless lives.
我真该让史坦尼斯把你们全部灭掉
I should have let Stannis kill you all.
提利昂
Tyrion.
你要招供吗
Do you wish to confess?
是  父亲
Yes, Father.
我有罪
I'm guilty.
有罪  您不就是想听这一句吗
Guilty. Is that what you want to hear?
你承认自己毒害了国王吗
You admit you poisoned the king?
不  这件事我是清白的
No, of that I'm innocent.
我犯的是更可怕的罪
I'm guilty of a far more monstrous crime.
我的罪就是生为侏儒
I am guilty of being a dwarf.
这不是一场对侏儒的审判
You are not on trial for being a dwarf.
噢  就是
Oh, yes, I am.
我的一生就是一场对侏儒的审判
I've been on trial for that my entire life.
你没有为自己辩护的吗
Have you nothing to say in your defense?
没有  只有一句
Nothing but this--
我没干过
I did not do it.
我没有杀乔佛里
I did not kill Joffrey,
但我希望是我干的
but I wish that I had.
看着你那恶毒的小混蛋死掉
Watching your vicious bastard die
比干一千个撒谎的妓女还要痛快
gave me more relief than 1,000 lying whores.
真希望我就是你们想象中的怪物
I wish I was the monster you think I am.
真希望我有足量的毒药毒死你们所有人
I wish I had enough poison for the whole pack of you.
看着你们吞进肚里  死了我也乐意
I would gladly give my life to watch you all swallow it.
马林爵士  马林爵士
Ser Meryn. Ser Meryn.
带犯人回牢房
Escort the prisoner back to his cell.
我绝不因为谋杀乔佛里而送命
I will not give my life for Joffrey's murder.
我知道在这儿得不到正义
And I know I'll get no justice here.
只能求助于天上诸神
So I will let the gods decide my fate.
我要求比武审判
I demand a trial by combat.